I'm scared.
Don't be scared.
Who is he?
He's gonna be your teacher.
This is a very good day.
Do you know why?
'Cause today is a beginning.
Your friend, Tobi?
Mmm-hmm.
I've known him
for a long time.
by other names.
Grandma Lois
knows him, too.
I had to learn, too.
It was hard at first.
But it was worth it.
Kristi, you're going
to grow up
and you're going to have a son
who is one of the chosen.
And, Katie,
your gift is your strength.
A lot is going to be
asked of you.
You're gonna have to
take care of your sister
and a lot of others.
There's a special girl
out there, a lot like you.
And he's going to
bring her to us.
What did you draw,
sweetie?
- Uncle Mike. Screaming.
- That's Uncle Mike?
Screaming?
Mmm-hmm.
Remember what we're
gonna do when he gets here?
- Boo!
- Like, real big. Boo!
Boo!
You want to practice again
before he gets here?
Boo!
Hey, hey, hey!
Remember what we're gonna do, okay?
Ooh.
Spooky. Why is
the door open?
Boo!
Oh, my gosh!
It's my favorite niece!
What's up, bro?
What is on that face of yours,
Uncle Mike?
What? Oh, you like this?
You fertilizing it?
Is that monsanto?
That's funny.
Is this a rental?
This is ridiculous!
I can't wait
to show you my room.
It's nice and cozy in here.
Two.
You have two rooms?
- Hey! How are you?
- Mommy, Mike's here.
Are you staying for a month?
That bag is massive!
Is there anything
in there for me?
- Hey, good to see you.
- We love Mike.
Hey!
You remember Skyler, right?
How are you?
I haven't seen you in forever.
Good. Yeah!
Hi.
Nice.
You look good.
Your mustache...
She's not European.
She's American.
Two weeks? Really?
I thought you said two days.
He just got dumped over email.
He's devastated.
Babe, his bag is his whole apartment.
It's huge.
Just making a rainbow.
It's okay.
Sorry.
Yeah, we didn't use
that vase, anyway.
Here's Uncle Mike.
Oopsie!
Why am I old
all of a sudden?
That's exactly what you're
gonna look like when you're old.
- I love this.
- Don't encourage.
What do you mean?
Sounds so good!
Leila, save the rest
for the talent show.
You come to
the talent show.
I'm gonna be there.
I don't have a date, though.
Because I left her
in Chicago.
Kinda why me and Chandra
called it quits,
'cause she didn't
want kids. I'm like...
Oh, yeah?
"I do. So, I'm leaving."
And then I left her.
So, that's...
But, yeah, you know,
I tried to tell her,
children are the future.
Look at that little
artist we got here.
I'm done with
my card, too.
Yeah...
Yeah, Merry Christmas.
Happy fucking holidays.
Festive.
Yoga retreat?
Is that what you said?
Yeah. It's a week-long
yoga retreat.
You're here for rehab, right?
No, I'm not here for rehab!
Let's be honest.
Just call it what it is.
I'm here for a yoga retreat!
Vodka? Vermouth?
What's your poison?
It's just yoga. And I thought
it'd be nice to come up here
and stay with these guys
for a week 'cause I miss them.
Kids love those.
Yeah, man. Check it out.
Oh, my God.
This is our Dad's old...
Santa suit.
I've added a little number...
Yeah?
- ...to the costume.
- Oh!
No, that's terrifying.
What?
That's terrifying.
It's jolly.
He's a rosy red...
He's angry.
Look at all the creases
on his forehead.
He has a beard.
I thought it would be magic.
He does have a beard.
It looks...
We might wanna run this by em.
You guys ready?
Your Dad will get electrocuted.
- Wait for it.
- Okay, step back.
Wait for it.
- This is lovely.
- Leila, you gotta tie it in a knot now,
tie it in a Christmas knot.
She's really got an eye.
I know I say this
every year.
No, you don't.
We missed a couple...
We missed a couple years, right?
My Grandmother
gave it to my Mom.
Your Grandma.
And your Grandma
gave it to me.
And you will
have it one day.
You got it?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, em,
that angel is gorgeous.
Yeah!
That was awesome!
Give me a high five.
I love her so much.
Okay.
I think I'm done
over here, buddy.
Yeah, yeah, it's...
Well, it's not abstract.
I think it's christmassy.
Looks great.
It'll look great in the front yard.
Yeah!
The neighbors will love it.
It's just two robust
reindeer going at it.
Two boys going at it.
Hey, bud, no judgment.
Why don't you actually
do some real work?
Go grab me a...
You did a great job!
There's a string of lights
in that box over there.
This box?
This is just caulk.
What?
It's caulk.
I think you got
the wrong box.
What is that?
That must be from the people who
used to live here.
There's tapes in here, too.
What?
Seriously?
Ha! It's working.
Nice.
Wow, this is creepy.
Too far.
Focused.
Ladies and gentleman,
award-winning cameraman...
It's so big!
...from outer space...
What is that?
Daddy!
How do you hold that?
That is huge.
- It's so big!
- "It's so big!"
You look so funny.
- People carried that?
- Yeah.
This is cool.
We own this.
Look at our box.
Yeah, it's cool.
Hey,
this thing is like...
I don't know if it's
out of focus or what,
but it's kinda like
picking up some trippy...
- That thing is ancient.
- Like these trails on the lights.
I'm seeing some sort of
odd shape in the middle of the room.
Some sort of blurry thing.
I think it's out of focus.
This thing is so wild.
- Oh, this is so weird.
- What?
I'm seeing something
in the middle of the room.
It's probably just old.
It's bizarre.
It's like a...
It's so weird.
It sounded like I was underwater when
I walked into this thing.
What is that?
What is this camera
picking up?
Hey, Mom. Got it.
She talked about it the entire way home.
She loved it.
Mike is going
to flip over this.
All right, sweetie.
You forgot to check.
Oh!
Bird is guarding the closet.
I'm gonna go in here.
Okay. Closet looks good.
Under the bed.
I don't see anything,
except for you.
- I don't see a teepee.
- The teepee.
- There's no teepee in your room.
You mean the pink tent?
We're all clear in here.
Wait. One last thing.
Will you hold this for a bit?
This thing is heavy!
Sleep tight.
Sweet dreams.
I can't wait for
Santa to come.
You can't? Well,
you know what?
He gives extra presents to little girls
who go to sleep.
Night, baby.
Love you.
Night, Mommy.
Where did it go?
Ryan?
Are you coming to bed?
I can't see the thing anymore.
I think it's gone.
Well, that's awesome.
You fixed it.
You can come to bed.
Play with that tomorrow.
No, I didn't
fix anything.
We went upstairs, came back,
and now it's completely gone.
If you come
to bed right now,
your wife is gonna
have sex with you.
Sex?
That's right.
I will have sex with you.
Oh!
That was supposed
to be sexy.
It's okay!
Stay in the mood!
This thing is absolutely sick.
It looks pretty sick.
The thing is...
You find anything?
...it's completely custom.
I mean, I've been
to 15 websites.
Nothing looks like this camera.
Traditionally, it has three picture tubes.
Uh-huh.
This one has six.
Oh, my God.
It seems like this has
multiple focus rings.
Like, I see "Iris"
and "focus,"
but this one right here?
Yeah.
I have no idea
what this does.
- Why are you so into this?
- It's just a camera.
I don't know.
It's sitting in my house.
I've never seen
any of this before.
I mean, this box?
I've never seen it before, Mike.
This guy.
I definitely picked
something up.
That's trippy.
Wow.
Okay. Can Mommy
and Daddy come?
What is this...
- Hey, Dad.
- Hey.
Is this the same thing?
Who were you talking to?
My friend.
Your friend?
Where's your friend?
Dad. I want to play
hide-and-seek.
Count to 10!
Okay.
One, two, three...
Where'd it go?
Right. The girls
are out tonight.
We got the house
to ourselves.
Why don't we take
the night off?
I got to get this game
out before Christmas break.
I was going through my bag.
Yeah? What'd you find?
Dirty underwear?
I found a souvenir
from my Belgium trip.
This is fine Belgian chocolate
wrapped up in a piece of foil?
Trust me, it doesn't
look like much.
It's been in your
pocket for a week?
It's not about the presentation.
They put a lot of time
into the chocolate.
Ryan, seriously, I know why you would
expect that from me.
And I appreciate it.
I know you pretty well.
I've been living with you
for a long time.
Fair enough.
I swear to God, it's not an edible.
He's talking to me.
Santa's the boss, man.
He's got a jolly attitude.
One night he only
has to work,
and he's flying around
in his sleigh
with the magic reindeer.
Mike, I just...
Sign me up, man.
I wish I could be like Santa.
Why do you still have
a VHS cassette player?
Did I ever tell you
that I stole Dad's old pornos.
And I was like,
"I need a way to watch these,"
so I got a VCR.
He had so many
weird, European...
He has one where this guy
wraps his balls in leather.
Do you know
about the Internet?
They all from '88 to '92?
I don't know.
Let's see what we got here.
Sit back.
That's not your house, man.
Where is this?
I don't know, dude.
- 1988.
- 1988. Oh!
There she is.
There she is!
This is gonna be so hot.
What is this?
What are we watching?
Oh, my God.
Oh, those shoulders.
I'm a shoulder guy,
apparently.
This is where
it gets real good.
Don't cry. Don't cry.
Go back...
Where'd your Mom go?
Hi!
Bye!
This sucks. Tell me
when the lady comes back.
I'll put in another tape.
Yeah. Look for one
marked "shoulders."
Fellas, how's
the game going?
Who's winning?
Why aren't you guys
talking to me?
I'm one of you!
Whoa! Ryan,
I think this...
This is wild, man.
Hey, Mike!
Next one's up and ready.
Give me some shoulder.
Check this out.
You sure
you're up for this?
Uh... oh, my God,
this is perfect!
Uh-huh.
- It's an earthquake.
- Holy shit!
Dennis, it's an earthquake!
No, no, no!
What is this?
How about "opening doors"?
Did they just
film everything?
This could be a porn.
Okay.
Think about it.
Focus, Kristi.
Don't use your eyes to see.
- Use what's inside you.
- Okay.
This is a little different.
What, is he hypnotizing her?
Concentrate, Kristi.
I need you to concentrate.
Concentrate on what, Kristi?
You see
through him, Kristi.
Let him show you
what he sees.
What the...
Let him
take you there.
Let him show you.
I hate this family.
There's a room.
Is this girl...
Is she just taking minutes?
Yeah.
For the meeting?
There's lots of colors.
I'm seeing colors,
too, buddy.
There's butterflies.
There's a big bird
over the door.
What's so funny?
There's a tent.
A tent?
What?
What? Ryan?
Like the one me and
Katie camp out in.
It's right in the little
girl's room.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
Why would it be in
the middle of the room?
Come on.
What am I missing?
The tent in the middle
of the room?
Butterflies? A bird
above the door?
Does this sound
like anything?
Uh... boredom?
She just described
Leila's room!
Oh, my God, man,
you're so fucking high!
Mike, she's describing
Leila's room.
Did you eat more
chocolate than I did?
Is he there, Kristi?
Ryan, come on, man,
turn this off. What are...
Shh!
Is he in the room?
Is he in the house?
Do you see him?
Why is he
making her do this?
Who's "him"?
He's there!
Whoa!
Did you trip a switch?
No, seriously,
I didn't trip a switch.
What did we do, blow a fuse
firing up that old VCR?
Okay, they're back.
That was strange.
Yeah.
- Did you hear that?
- Uh. Yeah.
Come with me.
Take your camera.
Go check it out yourself.
All right, fine. Here.
Concentrate.
I want you to focus, Ryan.
Dude, shut up.
That's ponytail.
Do you get what I'm doing?
Wait. Is that the same
stuff from the other night?
What's it doing?
Where did it go?
Mike?
Mike, it's not funny.
Is that you?
Holy shit.
Goal!
"Mike?"
"Mike, is that you?"
"Mike?" Oh, my God!
You scared
the shit out of me.
Ryan, I think...
This is crazy.
I think my camera is starting to see...
I think I'm seeing
something.
It's a...
It's a dipshit!
Do you see
the dipshit, man?
There's, like, particles of
dipshit in your aura, man.
It's right around your...
You're the dipshit, Ryan.
I'm calling you
a dipshit.
Oh, they're here! Hey!
- Hey, babe!
- Oh, Jesus!
That's Uncle Mike.
That's not a very good...
- Hold on a second.
- Mustache.
A big pile of...
That's not
a very good likeness.
So, what exactly
do you do again?
It's kind of like
feng shui.
I move the furniture around
so that, you know,
it's not blocking the energy.
Which I should probably
do with your house.
Really? Why?
Yeah.
It just feels
a little different.
Is your energy blocked, Mike?
Mike's energy?
I'm flowing nicely.
If you want to relieve
some sort of blockage...
I don't know what we're
talking about anymore.
Tell her about the night
we had last night.
Oh, I've just
kind of been
seeing and hearing
some strange things.
You know, I've heard of
Spirit Photography before,
but I've never actually
seen it in person.
What kind of stuff
have you been seeing?
Just shapes.
It could be a spirit
of some kind.
But most of the time,
these cameras,
they don't pick up on
beings as much as,
different planes of existence.
Somewhere where
a lot of displaced energy
would travel to.
But, you know, sometimes
it's just a camera glitch.
I don't know.
It's weird, but I don't think
this is a glitch.
I saw it in Leila's room,
and then last night
it was in the hall.
Guys, Leila's asleep.
We're taking off, okay?
Should be back around 11:00.
Good night.
Hey.
Be careful with that
camera. Seriously.
Relax, Ryan.
I just want to see
what this thing does.
Sky, you don't really think that
thing sees ghosts, right?
Yeah, I think
it's totally possible.
What?
Whoa! The lights look
so cool with this thing.
You should
see that on mushrooms.
Yeah, I'm gonna
need some wine.
Oh...
Okay. Um...
Red? White?
Like, Rosé.
Cabernet sauvi...
I think there's...
Hello?
Is somebody there?
Hey.
Jesus, you scared me.
It's just me.
I got the vino.
I think something's here.
What?
I think I felt something.
Okay.
Yeah, I looked through the camera,
but didn't see anything.
That's a timer.
Hold on, I think there's
a night-vision thing.
Oh, there it is.
What?
Probably just the wind.
Do you see anything?
No.
Mike, what do you see?
Let's go back inside.
Come on.
What the hell is that?
- Fuck! Something just flew out of the pool!
- Mike, quiet. You're gonna scare it.
Fuck that!
I'm gonna scare it?
Skyler.
Let me see the camera.
Whoa, what is this?
Mike, there's something here.
This is so crazy.
Leila!
Leila, honey,
what are you doing
out here, sweetie? It's cold.
Let's go inside.
It's cold, sweetie.
Yeah,
let's get you inside.
What the hell?
Fuck.
The stuff with
the pool was weird.
But she was way more
scared of it than I was.
Yeah.
I mean, maybe we saw something,
but the camera's janky.
We were coming
around the corner,
we turned and she was just
standing there.
Did you ask her
why she was here?
She was like comatose.
I don't know
if she heard us.
It was like
she was sleepwalking.
I don't know
what she was doing.
She's not a sleepwalker.
She sleeps real soundly.
Hey, guys,
look at this.
There's a hole in there.
- Are these yours?
- God, yeah!
It's my Rosary.
That's so weird.
Did you see her burying this stuff
out here last night?
No, I didn't see her,
but it's possible.
What are you doing?
You know how Daddy's
got a new toy.
Mmm-hmm.
Kind of like you have
all these toys.
Yeah.
Well, Daddy's new toy
saw something very
interesting last night.
I just...
You just... did you
feel something?
I don't want to
talk about him.
Who's "him," babe?
Uh...
Kristi,
what are you doing?
What this button does...
Go back to bed.
It's really late.
"Spirit Photography
is something that..."
Hello?
I don't know.
Maybe I'm going crazy.
Yram ydoolb.
Lee? What are you
doing in here?
Yram ydoolb.
Lee? Honey,
is that blood?
What's on your hand,
sweetie? You're bleeding.
What happened?
Honey, answer me.
You're bleeding.
Yram ydoolb.
What is she saying?
I don't know.
Bloody Mary.
Did you hear that?
Is she talking backwards?
Is she saying,
"bloody Mary"?
What's bloody Mary?
It's a game kids play.
What kind of game?
Originally in the game,
you say it three times
and a witch appears and shows you who
you're supposed to Marry.
But when I used to play it,
the way most kids play it,
you say "bloody Mary"
three times
and a bloody witch appears
and grabs you by the neck.
How would Leila
know about this game?
There's no way.
How old were you
when you played it?
I don't know. I was young.
Maybe her friends showed her.
- Go, man.
- Mike, what?
Check it out.
Check it out, man.
I cracked the case.
Right by the ferns, look.
They lived here?
They must've, right?
Why else would it be there?
1987?
So, this is the same house
where they filmed all that weird shit.
Whole place
burned down in '92.
No bodies were recovered.
Says the whole family just
disappeared, including...
Including their daughters,
Katie and Kristi.
So, you think
our daughter
is talking to a ghost?
Leila's been getting up at night and
playing with something
that only she and
this camera can see.
Kids do weird things.
It doesn't mean
the house is haunted.
The people who
lived here 20 years ago,
they put up cameras and
caught all kinds of things.
And our house is
built on top of theirs.
Did Mike put you up to this?
No. Look, look...
I feel like every time
he comes over,
you guys find some crazy
thing that you wanna do.
No, honey, it's not
like that at all. I promise.
I just want to see if there
really is something here
or if I'm just crazy.
Look, I'll feel better
either way.
Fine. Do it.
Yes? I can do it?
Yes, you can do it.
For a few days, Ryan.
All right, Mike.
That should just about do it.
Two cameras in here?
Yeah, well,
this other one's a control
to see if this one's
picking up something special.
And we'll put the other one
on the desk.
So we can watch
your daughter sleep all night.
Nothing weird about that.
"And she said, 'Sarah, Ashley, I've never
seen you look more beautiful.'
"and they turned
and looked at their Mom and waved
"and said, 'thanks, Mom.
We've never felt more beautiful.'
"the end."
Good night, sweetheart.
Mommy.
Mmm-hmm?
What?
Did I die?
When I was a baby?
No. Who did you
hear that from?
I don't know.
Well, there was
a cord in Mommy's tummy
and it got wrapped
around your neck,
and the doctors got scared
because it made it hard
for you to breathe.
So, they went in there real quick
and they got you out.
And there's nothing
wrong with you.
So there's nothing
to be worried about. Okay?
Okay.
'Cause you're
our little miracle.
And I love you. Okay?
Mmm.
I'm so sorry.
Right. Uh-huh.
What's going on?
Right. Okay.
Well, I'm gonna be there
in 15 minutes.
She bit a kid.
What? She bit a kid?
Yeah. She bit a kid at school and now
I gotta go pick her up.
Is the kid all right?
I don't know.
He had to go to the hospital.
I got to go pick her up now.
She can't stay at school.
They told me it took three teachers
to pull her off of him.
And then they were telling me
that the boy had to have stitches.
Like, this kid had to get stitches
from our daughter.
Maybe what the teacher
said is right.
Maybe we should send her
to a psychologist.
She's not sleeping, em.
She's been really quiet.
I mean,
I'm worried about her.
Okay.
Where?
Hey, sweetie,
what are you doing awake?
It's cold in here.
Get back under the covers.
Let's get you tucked back in.
There you go.
Just go back
to sleep, okay?
What was that?
It was nothing.
Okay, okay.
Okay, sweetie.
Why don't you lay down
and get some sleep?
Just get some sleep.
Hey, Lee.
I saw something in your
room last night with you and Auntie Skyler.
Honey?
What woke you up
last night?
Tobi did it.
Tobi did it?
Who's Tobi?
Leila, who's Tobi?
Leila?
It was this big, dark shape and it was
just floating around.
And she called it Tobi.
She's not scared
of it at all.
And I know you think
I'm losing my mind here,
but I think it's our ghost.
Emily thinks I'm nuts,
but remember I told you
Leila said her friend
Tobi woke her up last night, right?
Yeah.
Okay. Check this out.
This tape is from 1988.
Don't sit there.
That's Tobi's spot.
Oh, sorry. Is Tobi
sitting there right now?
They're talking about Tobi.
Sorry, Tobi.
Coincidence.
Four years later, these girls
have grown up a little bit,
- and we have ponytail.
- Mmm.
Tobi's a very important
part of your life.
Right?
Okay.
So, they stayed in touch
with Tobes. That was nice.
No. Mike...
Dude, this is
before Facebook.
It was hard to stay
in touch with people.
You think it's
a guy or girl?
Tobi would be
a cool stripper name.
Yeah.
"Coming down
to the main stage,
"please welcome Tobi."
I'm telling you,
the camera's not busted.
- It's seeing something that's there.
- It's a piece of shit, dude.
And besides,
Tobi is not a common name.
She probably watched the tape.
Mike, she's
three feet tall.
She has no idea
even what a VCR is.
She couldn't reach up there,
put it in and hit "play."
And get the right tape.
That makes me feel old.
Kids don't know what VCRs are?
What was that?
- Did you hear that?
- Yeah.
- You did?
- Yeah, man.
Are you seeing anything?
Holy shit.
What, are you
picking something up?
- Dude.
- What?
I think it's the icemaker
in the freezer!
Does Tobi like ice?
I think we should let him
out of the freezer, man.
Probably why he's
so ticked all the time.
There's too much of a coincidence.
That's all I'm saying.
Mike.
Keep it down, man.
Everyone's sleeping.
The sound came
from out there, dude!
Okay, give me the camera.
Give me the camera.
Mike, something's up there.
It's different, though.
It's moving.
Mike, it's moving.
Ryan, let's go.
We're gonna wake Leila.
I just want to
see where it went.
Do you see anything?
No. I'm not picking
anything up.
Oh, my God!
Ah... Jesus.
What the hell, man?
Daddy,
what are you doing?
I'm sorry, baby.
I'm sorry. It's okay.
Everything's okay, okay?
Just go back to sleep.
I screamed because you screamed.
You screamed so loud.
You shouted near your sleeping daughter's
face, so I screamed.
I couldn't see anything.
Know why I screamed?
Why?
Because I saw this
through the camera.
This seems more concentrated.
It's got more form.
It's darker.
And, dude, I fucking
felt that thing fly past me.
That looks like a face.
I mean, it's not human.
But that's crazy, Mike.
Why do you still need
two cameras in here?
I just don't think one camera
can cover the whole room.
It's talking to her and
telling her to do things,
and it's not just
in her room.
It's moving all around
the house.
I just want to know where
it's going and what it wants.
That's better.
Now?
Take me away.
Lee!
Put those down!
Put those down. Right now.
What are you doing?
Did you turn
the gas on?
Leila, you cannot
play with matches.
You can't turn
the gas on.
What are you doing?
Get back in bed. Okay.
Don't play with matches.
It's the middle of the night.
Ry? Ryan? Ryan.
That Bible is my
Bible from upstairs.
It was in the fireplace.
That's what she
was trying to burn.
The Rosary that she
tried to bury,
it was also
in the fireplace.
She said she was
playing a game.
What kind of game can you
play with matches?
She said she was
playing a game with Tobi.
She just knew you had
the book up there.
She probably doesn't
know what it is.
I don't know.
I put her back to bed
and then I come down here,
and then the Angel falls.
I don't know, it just...
It doesn't seem like her.
It seems like she's different.
I didn't want to believe it,
but I think Ryan's right.
There is something in our house.
Lee, I need you
to tell me
that you're gonna
stop talking to Tobi.
Lee?
Lee,
look at your mother.
Can you look
at me, please?
Tobi is my friend.
Lee, he's not your friend.
He is not... no.
Okay? And Mommy and Daddy don't want
you talking to him anymore.
Lee, promise us
you're gonna stop talking to Tobi.
I promise.
Good.
So, the tapes
start in '88.
Lots of Katie and Kristi stuff.
And they're living
with their Mom.
Shoulders!
Right.
Why does
he need a bowl?
He wants to eat.
I haven't gone
through all the tapes.
But the footage
suddenly jumps
and everything
is real different.
There's nothing in between?
No.
The Mom and her boyfriend?
They're completely
absent in the footage.
Like, nowhere?
Not on any of the tapes.
And this weird cult is taking
care of these girls now.
And they're calling
this other woman Mom.
Is that a milk bath?
I had one more dream.
Who are these people?
Jesus.
It's just that
I had another Mommy.
And then she fell down
some sort of stairs.
Tobi said you're
on your way, sweetie.
You're progressing nicely.
What does all this mean?
I don't know.
But this guy is their leader
and it's like he's preparing
the girls for something.
You'll make us
so proud.
He needs her.
We're getting close.
Still watching tapes?
Yeah.
I just wanna see
if there's a connection.
Didn't we watch this
the other night?
No,
it's a different night.
But she's doing
the same thing.
They literally do this every night.
It's like a ritual.
It's not a normal
home video.
It's like some sort
of training tape.
Is he showing you?
I'm not sure.
It's too blurry.
Just let him
show you what he sees.
Let him guide you.
I think I see food.
Yeah, I'm pretty
sure it's food.
It's just so
messy and blurry.
I see
a TV.
What?
I see a lot of TVs.
What the...
I think she's seeing this.
How is that possible?
I see toys.
Dude.
I see bunches of toys.
I see people.
Brothers.
Fuck.
I'm pretty sure.
I think they're brothers.
Whoa, dude.
What the fuck?
I think they're
watching me.
They're talking about us.
Stay with him.
Only he can do this.
Some bizarre shit.
Only he can be there.
Daddy! I can't sleep.
What are you
doing awake, huh?
What's going on?
Tell me.
You're making so much noise.
I'm making too much noise?
Daddy'll go up and make
sure everything...
Bless you.
- Okay.
- What the...
Wait, Ry, did you...
What the...
So, this is the tape I was telling you
about from last night. Check it out.
You hear noises
in your room?
Daddy'll go up and
make sure everything's...
Bless you.
- Wait. Play that again.
- So, here, I blew it up.
Look. Leila sneezes,
and then Kristi says, "bless you."
Daddy'll go up and
make sure everything's...
Bless you.
These people,
I think they're watching us.
And I know these tapes
are from 20 years ago.
But they can see what's
happening here with us and with Leila.
There's a door?
Really?
Where does it go?
And I can go there?
All I have to do
is draw it?
Okay.
Oh, my God.
What is all this?
I don't think
these are just scribbles.
I think there's
a pattern to these.
Some of these look familiar.
I know I've seen
this stuff before.
Those symbols on Leila's wall?
They're on the tapes too,
in the girls' room.
That symbol there?
It's used by a coven
called the Midwives.
You mean like Witches?
These Midwives go all the
way back to the middle ages.
Oh, my God.
They were into Devil worship.
They would use
symbols like this
to open these doorways
to different places and times.
What is that?
I don't know.
Sounds like it's in
Leila's room.
What is that?
I don't know.
Em, there's something coming
from that recorder.
Be careful.
Honey, what are
you doing?
Baby, what?
What are you doing?
Honey. Honey.
Lee!
What the fuck?
Baby.
Lee, are you okay? Honey.
Baby, baby, breathe.
Breathe, baby.
Calm down.
Okay, good girl.
Breathe. Good girl.
What were you doing?
He's gonna take me away.
Who's gonna take you away?
What was that?
I don't know.
What is that?
Is something out there?
I don't know.
What the fuck?
Just keep looking.
I'm gonna go check on Skyler.
Mike!
Mike, what are you doing?
Mike. Joke's over, man.
It's not funny, Mike.
Mike.
- Ryan.
- Ah!
What?
What are you doing?
Oh, no.
Did you see that?
What? No.
There was somebody right here.
No,
I don't see anything.
- You didn't see it?
- No.
Fuck.
Look, she's sleeping.
What did you see?
There's no one in here.
What the fuck?
What is that?
I don't know.
I don't see anything.
There's nothing
fucking there.
Fuck!
Get Leila! Let's go!
Get out of here!
Oh, my...
What was that?
Fuck!
Hi, please. Can I talk to
father Michael, please?
Our house has been...
We think it's like haunted
or something and something's
affecting our daughter...
I was on hold, but I'm looking to
speak with father Alessio? Right.
I'll just call him back
at 4:00. Thank you.
She's been acting strange.
And things have just been
starting to happen
more and more and we really
don't know what to do.
Baby Jesus.
Here's Mary.
She's going to have
a special baby.
That's right. She is.
Do you remember us coming
into your room last night
when you were
on your recorder?
Well, when we
came in there
and put you
back to bed,
you said, "he's gonna
take me away."
Who's gonna take you away?
Do you mean Tobi?
Would you please answer me?
Lee, please answer me.
Lee?
Answer your Mom.
Lee.
Where is he gonna take you?
To be with the others.
Hi. This is my
wife, Emily.
Hi. How are you?
We're so grateful that you're here.
Thank you so much.
I just hope I can be
of help to you guys.
I think you can.
We'll explain everything to you.
This camera picks up stuff
that none of our other cameras can see.
It's wild.
And you're sure nothing
unusual was happening
in the house before
you started to use it?
No.
I've seen this camera on these
tapes from 20 years ago.
It's like they were using the camera to
see this stuff, too.
Father, watch this.
It started out small.
Right?
I thought it was
just a glitch.
It's getting darker when you
see it through the camera?
And bigger,
like it's growing.
Look at this dark figure
that moves through the door.
Either of you ever experienced anything
like this before,
here or any other place?
- Nothing like this.
- I found this tape of these girls playing bloody Mary,
the same game Leila was
playing the other night.
What if she learned
this from them?
They would tape themselves
doing these weird rituals.
You're doing so well.
Tobi is going to be so proud of you.
You think this is the Tobi that
Leila speaks of?
- Yeah.
- We think so.
Has she used any other name
besides Tobi?
No. Just Tobi.
Why?
Sometimes spirits will tend to
hide their own identities,
their true nature.
They'll use another name.
From what you describe,
from what I know,
which is very little,
it sounds as if
your daughter
may be being stalked
by a Demon or
a demonic presence.
If this is happening,
we should go.
We should get out now.
We need to
leave the house!
I never noticed anything before.
Demons do not haunt houses,
they haunt people.
If you leave this house,
it will definitely follow you.
Demons feed on fear.
The more attention you give,
the stronger it grows,
the bigger it grows.
You run away, it follows.
You can't just ignore
what's happening
in the house, father.
Would it be all right
if I spoke with your daughter?
- Would that be okay?
- Yeah.
We have a guest here.
He's our friend.
He's a really nice man.
Stop.
She's a little shy.
Does that name mean
anything to you?
No. Why? Should it?
I want you
to meet somebody.
Oh, here she comes.
Is this your friend?
Does your friend
have a name?
Don't tell me.
Let me see.
Griselda?
Tell him his name.
Is it Geraldine?
It's Bubba,
isn't that right, baby?
Oh, I like
the name Bubba.
That's a great name.
Bubba looks really hot.
Can I give Bubba
a little bath?
Can I put some
water on him?
Let me just give
Bubba a little water.
Oh, Bubba likes it.
He's very happy.
Can I give you a little
water on your head?
Make you feel cool?
How about that, hmm?
Much better, huh?
Yeah.
You feel better now?
So, what are you and
Bubba gonna do today?
You have a secret for me?
Hmm?
What is it, honey?
Oh, my God!
I'm so sorry.
This is nothing like her.
It's fine.
I'm all right.
Look. I just want you
to take care of your daughter.
Okay?
Okay.
I'll be back soon.
Stay calm, stay relaxed.
She fucking bit a priest.
After what father Todd said,
I went back and
did more research.
I found this tape
in the camera.
I thought it was blank.
But look.
- Wait! That's your house. - Yeah, Look at the date.
It's three days before we moved in.
...very happy
with this house.
It's a good house
for him.
You hear that?
I think it's that leader guy talking.
I don't know, man.
Maybe it's just
a contractor or something.
This is a good space.
They've done a wonderful job.
See, Ryan, he's just
talking about the house, that's all it is.
Very good entry
point in here.
No. He said
"entry point."
The fact that we moved
into this specific house
of all the houses
we looked at...
It just doesn't seem like
a coincidence to me.
No, no, not Higgins.
Hubbard. H-u-b-b...
Right, Hubbard.
Katie Hubbard.
That's what I've been...
That's impossible.
Because I'm looking
at her card
and your number
is on her card.
They're saying they've
never heard of her.
She never worked for them.
We weren't even looking in
this neighborhood, remember?
And we thought the deal
was too good to be true.
Yeah.
Remember that?
Where did she come from?
How did you meet her?
I called the agency today.
They have no record that
she ever worked there.
Nobody had ever
heard of her.
What? But that's...
What if, like...
What if someone
placed us here on purpose?
If somebody conspired
for us to be in this house?
Do you think that
could be possible?
Where did she come from?
Sure you want to do this?
Yeah.
You need some sleep, sweetie.
Wake me up if anything happens.
Okay?
All right. I left
a message with father Todd.
Hopefully he calls us back.
What the fuck?
Emily, wake up.
What?
Did you hear that?
Something knocked the camera
over in the hallway.
You didn't hear anything?
No.
Hey, sweetie.
Sweetie, sorry.
Go back to bed.
Sweetie, go back to
sleep now, all right?
Don't be scared, Mommy.
Stay here.
Ryan, what's going on
up there, man?
- What was that noise?
- I'm not sure.
What do you see?
There's nothing here.
Mike.
I think I see something.
What?
- You see something?
- Don't move.
- Do you see...
- Stay still.
Is something here?
Mike, stay calm.
You heard what father Todd said.
Just don't move.
Oh, fuck. Holy fuck.
Mike, run, run!
Something...
I felt something on my neck!
I felt something!
It was fucking huge, Mike.
Holy fuck. I don't know
where he went.
Fuck!
What was that?
Shit.
What the fuck, dude?
Wait, wait, wait.
I see it.
It's over by the tree.
- What the fuck?
- I don't know.
Dude!
Oh, my God.
Ryan, where is it?
Do you see it?
Emily, stay upstairs!
Lock the door!
In the kitchen!
Shit! Fuck!
What do you see?
Fuck me, Ryan!
Next time I'm just
gonna stay at Mom's!
God!
- You all right?
- No!
It fucking touched me, dude!
Did you see
the keyboard move, dude?
What the fuck?
I don't see anything.
What the fuck's going on?
I don't know.
Fuck,
it's getting closer.
It's in the doorway.
Where is it? What?
The doorway to the kitchen.
He came through the door!
He's in the room with us.
What the fuck?
Hey! Fuck, go!
Jesus Christ!
Go, Mike, go, go, go!
Fuck! What the fuck? Shit!
I don't see anything.
What the fuck, man?
What the fuck was that?
What the fuck is wrong
with your house?
When you grow up,
you're going to take care of
your sister and a lot of others.
Because the two of you
are going to help us find other
special people just like you.
Ah!
What the fuck?
Em! Emily.
Oh, my God.
What the fuck?
What the fuck
did that to him?
I think it was Tobi
that broke that guy's back.
It seems like he's getting bigger
and more powerful, em.
I mean, what if they put him
here to kill us like they did this guy?
We need to take it
to the police.
You think they can help?
They have to be able
to say something.
They have to know
something about this.
You don't think they're
gonna think I'm crazy?
Who gives a fuck
if they think we're crazy?
This is fucking crazy.
Skyler will be home soon.
Mike and I will be as quick as possible.
All right?
Okay.
Just stay with Leila.
I love you. We'll be back as soon
as we can, all right?
Would you like some tea?
Hey.
Let's go downstairs and play.
Lee, come on. We have games
that we can play downstairs.
No, I'm fine here.
How about me and you
get out of the house?
Come on, we can
go outside.
We can go on the seesaw,
your favorite thing.
This is where
I want to be now.
Let's go downstairs.
We can play down there.
It's just you and me, okay?
I said I'm fine.
Honey, I don't want to be
in this room, okay?
I don't really want to be in this room,
so let's go downstairs.
Mommy, I said I'm fine here.
That's enough!
We're going downstairs right now.
I'm fine here.
Is there someone
in this room?
Leila, are you talking
to somebody in this room?
Oh, my God.
Leila! Leila! Oh, my God!
Open the door.
Leila, open this door!
Lee!
Where is she?
God. Where the fuck did it go?
Lee, let's go.
We're getting outta here.
Go. Lee.
Oh, God!
Where the fuck are you?
Leave my daughter alone!
What are you looking for?
I know I saw it somewhere.
Just a tape, Mike.
Just a tape.
Skyler, how's em?
She need anything?
She's in her room with Leila.
They're resting.
What are you guys doing?
I found this
down at the police station.
Leila and hunter
have the same birthday?
That has to be
a coincidence.
Yeah. One hell of
a coincidence, right?
June 6th, 2005.
Kristi's son is born on
the exact same day as Leila.
They haven't found him yet?
No. Katie is his aunt.
She killed Kristi
and the Dad.
They even think she killed
this family in Nevada.
Cops have been looking
for her for years.
Wait. Here it is.
Look, there he is.
There he is, right there.
I knew I'd seen
this kid before.
Look. Look.
Tell me that's not him.
This tape is from
1992, Skyler.
So, the kid
wasn't even born yet.
How did he get there?
I can't explain it.
He and Leila have
the exact same birthday.
What if this is where
Tobi's gonna take Leila?
Hey, sweetie.
Whatcha doing?
You waiting for Santa Claus?
He's not gonna be here
for a few days.
Get away from me.
I'm putting this camera
back in her room.
We need to keep
an eye on her.
Look, father Todd said
he would come back and help.
We just need to stay calm.
Come get some rest.
Leila,
come play with me.
- Leila? Leila!
- Where is she?
- Leila!
Leila!
Lee!
- What's going on?
- We can't find Leila!
What?
I don't know where
she went! Leila!
- Leila!
Ry! That was
Leila's room!
- Leila!
- Lee? Baby.
Leila!
My baby, where
were you, honey?
Hey, sweetie. Hey.
Where were you, baby?
Where were you?
Cold. Talk to me.
Talk to Daddy.
Are you okay?
I'm going to set
him free, Daddy.
- Let's go! We're leaving right now!
- No! I'm not going.
Honey, stop it!
We love you.
Stop screaming.
I'm not going!
Hello?
Do you see anything?
Clear.
Let's make this quick.
In here somewhere.
Do you see anything?
No, I'm not
picking anything up.
I'm not crazy, right?
It feels different in here.
It doesn't feel as bad.
Yeah, it does.
It's like a different place.
Should we call
them at the hotel?
No, let's let them sleep.
I bet they're exhausted.
Oh, em said make sure
to grab a jacket for Leila.
Okay.
Do you see anything?
No.
Oh, wait. What's that?
Did that happen
last night?
I don't remember
seeing it before.
I'm not seeing anything.
You okay?
What is that?
Don't know.
Just found them.
Okay, let's...
Let's get the fuck
out of here.
Ready to go?
Just a sec.
Come on.
We should get back.
It's getting dark.
Look at all this stuff.
Ryan's been going crazy.
This is the research he was
talking about at the hotel.
Look at this.
Holy shit.
That's like Leila's drawing.
It looks like it.
"Revelations 5:6."
"The slain lamb will be
used against God,
"for the blood of
the chosen ones will taint it
"and help give life to one
of the seven princes of Hell.
"Each prince shall return
through the blood
"of the two born
of the same moon."
That's Leila and hunter.
It's their blood.
What if the witches are using
them in some kind of ritual
to give Tobi
a human body?
What? Skyler,
what does this mean?
What was that?
What is that?
Is that the door?
- What was that?
- The front door's open.
- Did you lock it?
- Yes.
Hello?
Em? Ry?
Skyler...
I'm just checking.
Hello?
What was that?
It was Leila's room.
Didn't we leave
that door open?
I don't remember.
Leila? Leila?
What are you doing?
What...
You've got to stop,
sweetie. Leila, stop.
Leila. No, no, no,
stop, sweetie.
Answer me. Leila,
where's your Mom and Dad?
Where's your
Mom and Dad?
Leila!
I am the bringer of he.
What?
Who's "he"?
Leila, no, honey.
Leila, stop.
Stop. Leila, stop.
Do you mind
if I touch your hands, honey?
She just, uh,
showed up here?
Yeah. We were at a hotel,
six miles away.
We went to sleep
for two minutes.
I have no idea how she got here.
She was gone.
Can we have a chat
in the kitchen?
Yeah. Hey, Sky,
could you take her?
I've spoken to someone
outside the church.
There's only one way
to save your daughter.
But I have serious reservations about
what they proposed.
Father, you are
the only one who believes us.
You have to help us.
We have to do something.
If we don't,
we'll end up like
hunter Rey and
his family.
An exorcism is a remedy
for someone who's possessed.
I do not think that's what's
happening right here.
What do we need?
What's happening?
We need an extermination.
Emily,
do you have them?
We need to soak those
sheets in Holy water.
It'll subdue the Demon
and protect us against him.
Ryan, your daughter
was born on June 6th,
2005. Right?
It's the sixth day
of the sixth month
of the sixth year,
2005. 666.
I believe this
is no coincidence.
She's part of the prophecy.
The Witches on those tapes,
the Midwives?
I think their job is
to give demons life,
to allow them to
walk the earth.
They targeted your daughter
to help them do so.
You understand how serious this is?
- Yeah.
- So, we need to trap this thing using
your daughter as bait.
Downstairs, we'll draw
the key of Solomon.
Once the Demon is lured
inside the trap, we're gonna
cover it with sheets
and burn it back to Hell.
The blessing of the father almighty
be upon this creature of salt
and let all malignity
and hindrance
be cast forth hence
and let all good enter.
In the name of the Holy spirit.
Amen.
I'll go check on Leila.
The blessing of the father almighty be
upon this creature of salt...
That's good. Skyler, make sure
the line is straight. Okay?
Complete the key and
make sure it's straight.
How's Leila? She okay?
She's doing okay.
Emily's with her.
That's perfect.
Can you help? Please.
Sheets and Holy water.
Bring it over. Thank you.
I'll try to lure the Demon
out into the circle.
We're gonna trap that thing.
Scatter salt around
the perimeter.
All around the perimeter.
St. Michael the Archangel,
defend us in battle.
May God rebuke him,
we humbly pray,
and do thou
as the prince...
Tobi?
I think so.
Keep doing
what you're doing.
We need to keep
provoking him.
Be our protection
against the wickedness
and snares of the Devil.
Father,
something's happening!
St. Michael, the Archangel,
defend us in battle.
Why is everything shaking?
What's happening?
...and do thou, o prince
of the heavenly host...
Keep calm, everyone.
By the power of God,
cast into Hell Satan
and all the evil spirits.
Body of Christ...
Cast into Hell Satan
and all the evil spirits.
Water flowing from
the side of Christ,
wash me clean.
Oh, my God!
What is going on?
Emily, go get Leila.
It's time. It's time!
- Get in the circle.
Everybody,
get in the circle.
Come with me.
Everybody
in the circle. Now!
Hail, Mary, full of grace.
The lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou
amongst women...
Hail, Mary, full of grace.
The lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou
among women
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb. Jesus.
Father,
what happened to her eyes?
Why are they black?
Leila!
What's happening to her?
He knows what
you're doing.
- Oh, my God!
- What happened?
Ryan,
what's going on?
Father Todd!
Stay in the circle!
What do you see?
- What's happening?
- Ryan, what do you see?
Where's father Todd?
You see him?
Where'd he go?
What do you see?
Father?
No!
Oh, my God!
Where did he go?
What are we gonna do?
We need father Todd
for this all to work!
Hold on to Leila!
Stay close! Hold on!
Get back! Get back
into the circle!
Where is it?
Get back!
I see it!
Get in the circle!
Get back!
Mike! Get the sheets!
We got to get the sheets!
Come on, we've got
to put it on him!
Emily, grab the camera.
What do you see?
We got to say the prayers!
Get the book!
Is it working?
Skyler! The Bible!
Hurry!
We have to finish this!
Here, I have it.
"In the name of
Jesus Christ, our lord,
"Mary, mother of God,
"behold the cross
of the lord,
"flee bands of enemies.
"We drive you from us.
"Whoever you may be,
Unclean spirits..."
"Pray, therefore,
the God of peace,
"to crush Satan
beneath our feet."
Oh, my God,
it worked!
Lee! You okay?
Mommy? Daddy?
Sweetie, are you back?
What happened?
You're back.
She's back. It worked.
- It worked?
- It worked!
She okay?
Yeah. Let's get
out of here. Let's go.
Skyler!
Mike, no! No!
Leila!
Leila, come back here!
Come back!
Leila!
Lee! Lee, stop!
Ryan, I dropped the camera!
Just go get Leila!
Leila, stop! Please!
Leila!
Ryan! Ryan!
Oh, fuck! Oh, fuck!
Leila! Leila!
Oh, God, what is this?
What the fuck?
What the fuck is that?
What the fuck
is that?
Oh, God. Oh, no.
Stay away!
Oh, God, what is this?
Lee?
Leila!
Leila, it's Mommy.
Leila?
Oh, fuck!
Where is she?
You're too late.
What have you
done with her?
The darkness.
It's coming.
What?
Where is my daughter?
Fuck!
Where is it?
Where is my daughter?
Where is she?
You're too late, Emily.
It's done.
He's real now.
No. No,
you tell me where she is.
Tell me where she is!
Where is she? Leila!
Oh, my God.
What is that?
My God, what the...
Oh, God.
Oh, God...
Oh, God. Leila!
Oh, baby, hi. Are you okay?
Are you okay?
I'm okay, Mommy.
They just needed
one drop of my blood.
What? Where did they cut you?
What did they do to you?
Oh, baby, your hand.
He's alive now, Mommy.
He's real, just like
you and me.
Shh. What are you
talking about?
What did they
say to you, baby?
Oh, God. Stay back.
Stay back, stay back.
Stay away from us.
Stay away from us!
Go, Leila, go!
Please, you've gotten
what you wanted.
You got what you wanted.
Please, leave us alone.
Hi, Tobi.
www.YTS.AG